Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Kathryn.
我是Kathryn。
And today we're talking about office stuff, things in your office.
今天我们要聊聊办公室里的那些事儿，也就是你办公室里的东西。
That's right.
没错。
We are talking about secrets in the office or maybe specific little things that people
我们要聊的是办公室里的秘密，或者说是人们
talk about behind other people's back.
在背后议论的一些小事。
Okay, bad things then.
好吧，那就是些不好的事情了。
So this is an elementary level lesson.
这是一节初级课程。
Before we get going though, let's take a look at a phrase in today's vocabulary preview.
不过在我们开始之前，先来看看今天词汇预览中的一个短语。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So the phrase for today is actually the same as the title for this lesson and that's office
今天的短语实际上和这节课的标题一样，就是办公室
gossip.
八卦。
Okay, you all know what an office is.
好吧，大家都知道办公室是什么。
What is gossip?
那八卦是什么呢？
So to gossip means to talk about other people secretly or behind their backs or maybe talk
八卦的意思就是偷偷地或在背后议论别人，或者谈论
about other people's problems or private things.
别人的问题或私事。
So oh my God, did you hear?
所以，哦，天哪，你听说了吗？
John is totally going to break up with her.
John 完全要和她分手了。
So you're talking about people without them knowing.
所以你是在别人不知情的情况下谈论他们。
Right.
没错。
So you're talking about their private things, their relationships, maybe you're even maybe
所以你是在谈论他们的私事、他们的关系，甚至可能还在
criticizing them.
批评他们。
That's right.
对。
So office gossip is talking about people in your office without them knowing.
所以办公室八卦就是在同事不知情的情况下谈论他们。
So saying bad things about them.
就是说他们的坏话。
Right.
对。
So without any more delay, why don't we listen to this dialogue for the first time.
那就不多说了，我们先来听一遍这段对话吧。
Hey, Eric, have you heard?
嘿，埃里克，你听说了吗？
No, go on.
没有，快说。
Tell me.
告诉我。
What's the latest office gossip?
最近有什么办公室八卦？
Well, you didn't hear this from me, but the rumor is Paula is getting a promotion.
嗯，你可别说是从我这儿听说的，但传闻是宝拉要升职了。
No way.
不可能。
But she's a terrible worker and you can't trust her.
但她工作表现很差，而且你没法信任她。
She's so two faced.
她太两面三刀了。
You can't believe anything she says.
她说什么都不能信。
Hey guys, what are you two whispering about?
嘿，你们俩在嘀咕什么呢？
Oh, hi, Paula.
哦，嗨，宝拉。
How are you?
你好吗？
I've got some good news.
我有好消息。
I'm getting a promotion.
我要升职了。
Congratulations.
恭喜你。
Eric and I were just saying that you were the best person for the job.
埃里克和我刚才还在说你是最适合这个职位的人。
Yes, you're the best.
是啊，你是最棒的。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So we have four key words that we want to look at from this gossip dialogue.
所以，从这个八卦对话中，我们要看四个关键词。
So why don't we take a look at those now in Language Takeaway.
那我们不如在“语言要点”环节来看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, the first word is rumor.
好的，第一个词是“rumor”。
Rumor.
谣言。
Now this is an interesting word about gossip.
这是一个关于八卦的有趣词。
Yeah, a rumor.
是的，谣言。
So a rumor is a story that might or might not be true.
所以谣言是一个可能真实也可能不真实的故事。
Right.
对。
Okay, so I heard a rumor that they broke up yesterday.
好的，我听到一个谣言说他们昨天分手了。
Okay, so you're not sure if they broke up or no one has told you for a fact.
好的，所以你不确定他们是否分手了，或者没人确切告诉你。
No, it means I probably heard it from someone else who heard it from someone else who heard
不，这意味着我可能是从别人那里听说的，那个人又从另一个人那里听说的，那个人又
it from someone else who doesn't really know.
从另一个不太了解情况的人那里听说的。
Right.
没错。
So rumors are maybe guesses about people and you don't know if they're true.
所以，谣言大概就是关于别人的猜测，你不知道它们是不是真的。
You see this a lot with famous people, movie stars.
你在名人、电影明星身上经常看到这种情况。
They always talk about rumors that maybe they got married in secret or something.
他们总是谈论谣言，比如他们可能秘密结婚了之类的。
Exactly.
正是。
There's a rumor that Angelina Jolie and Brad Pitt are breaking up.
有传言说安吉丽娜·朱莉和布拉德·皮特要分手了。
Right.
对。
Okay, so we don't know if it's true.
好吧，所以我们不知道这是不是真的。
Rumor.
谣言。
That's a rumor.
那就是个谣言。
So now the rumor that they heard was that this girl Paula is getting a promotion.
所以他们听到的谣言是，这个叫宝拉的女孩要升职了。
Promotion.
升职。
This is an important office word.
这是个重要的办公室用语。
This means to be offered a better job in your company.
这意味着在公司里得到一个更好的职位。
That means to move up.
也就是往上走。
To move up.
往上走。
Right.
没错。
Alright, so this is a noun.
好了，所以这是个名词。
You get a promotion, right?
你得到升职，对吧？
Yes, I got a promotion last year which also meant I got more money.
是的，我去年升职了，这也意味着我涨了工资。
Okay, awesome.
好的，太棒了。
So that is a promotion.
所以那就是升职。
Now when they were talking about the promotion, the girl said, I can't believe, the guy said,
当他们谈论升职时，那个女孩说“我简直不敢相信”，那个男的说，
and Eric said, I can't believe she's getting a promotion.
埃里克说：“我简直不敢相信她要升职了。”
She's so two-faced.
她太两面三刀了。
Two-faced.
两面三刀。
So think about what this means.
所以想想这是什么意思。
To have two faces.
有两张脸。
To be two-faced means to have two different sides to your personality.
两面三刀意味着你的性格有两面。
A good one and a bad one.
一面好，一面坏。
So like, I can be very nice to Marco.
比如，我可以对马可非常友好。
Marco, wow, you look so good today.
马可，哇，你今天看起来真棒。
You're such a nice guy.
你真是个好人。
You're such a hard worker.
你工作真努力。
And then, oh my God, Marco's such an idiot.
然后，哦天哪，马可真是个白痴。
He's like never working and he's always on the phone.
他好像从不工作，总在打电话。
Oh, hi Marco.
哦，嗨，马可。
How are you doing?
你好吗？
That is two-faced.
那就是两面三刀。
That's very good.
那很好。
Alright, so two-faced means to have two different sides to your personality.
好了，所以两面三刀意味着你的性格有两面。
Now it's interesting the way that you use this word, you say two-faced, right?
有趣的是，这个词的用法是你说“two-faced”，对吧？
So you have to add the E-D at the end.
所以你得在末尾加上“-ed”。
You can't say he is two-faced.
你不能说“he is two-faced”。
No.
不。
Or he has two-face.
或者“he has two-face”。
No, it's an adjective.
不，它是一个形容词。
So he's two-faced.
所以是“he's two-faced”。
Okay.
好的。
She is two-faced.
她是两面三刀的。
Okay, two-faced.
好的，两面三刀。
I don't like people who are two-faced.
我不喜欢两面三刀的人。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And we have one final word and it's actually a verb when people talk like this.
我们还有一个词，实际上是一个动词，当人们这样说话时。
When they're talking like this.
当他们这样说话时。
So they're talking quietly.
所以他们小声说话。
Very quietly.
非常小声。
To whisper.
耳语。
Okay.
好的。
So what are you whispering about?
所以你们在耳语什么？
Uh-oh.
哦哦。
So usually when people are whispering, they're talking about a rumor.
所以通常当人们耳语时，他们在谈论谣言。
Right.
对。
Or they're talking in secret.
或者他们在秘密交谈。
You don't want somebody else to hear you.
你不想让别人听到。
Right.
对。
So when you want to be very quiet, like at the movie theater, you whisper.
所以当你想非常安静时，比如在电影院，你就耳语。
Whisper.
耳语。
Okay.
好的。
So those are four words for language takeaway.
所以这是语言学习的四个词。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to take a look at
我们为什么不回去，再听一遍对话，然后回来看看
a couple of phrases.
几个短语。
Psst.
嘘。
Hey, Eric, have you heard?
嘿，埃里克，你听说了吗？
No.
没有。
Go on, tell me.
说吧，告诉我。
What's the latest office gossip?
办公室最近有什么八卦？
Well, you didn't hear this from me, but the rumor is Paula is getting a promotion.
嗯，你可别说是从我这儿听说的，但谣言是宝拉要升职了。
No way.
不可能。
But she's a terrible worker and you can't trust her.
但她工作很差劲，而且你不能信任她。
She's so two-faced.
她太两面三刀了。
You can't believe anything she says.
她说的任何话你都不能信。
Hey guys, what are you two whispering about?
嘿，你们俩在嘀咕什么呢？
Oh, hi Paula.
哦，嗨，宝拉。
How are you?
你好吗？
I've got some good news.
我有好消息。
I'm getting a promotion.
我要升职了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Eric and I were just saying that you were the best person for the job.
埃里克和我刚才还在说你是最适合这个职位的人。
Yes, you're the best.
是的，你是最棒的。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have three key phrases from this great dialogue on Fluency Builder.
所以现在我们从这段精彩的对话中得到了三个关键短语，用于流利度训练。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So this first one is the beginning to any great rumor.
所以第一个是任何大谣言的开始。
We say, have you heard?
我们说：“你听说了吗？”
Right.
对。
So, have you heard?
所以，你听说了吗？
Have you heard that she got a promotion?
你听说她升职了吗？
Right.
没错。
It's kind of, you're not really asking, right?
这有点像，你其实不是在问问题，对吧？
Although it is a question, have you heard?
虽然这是个问句，“你听说了吗？”
But you're not really expecting an answer.
但你并不真的期待一个回答。
This means I'm going to tell you some gossip.
这意味着我要告诉你一些八卦。
Right.
没错。
Have you heard?
你听说了吗？
Because maybe I did, maybe I didn't, but I'm still going to say it.
因为也许我听说了，也许没有，但我还是会说出来。
I'm still going to say it anyway.
我还是会说出来，不管怎样。
So usually you can say, what?
所以通常你可以说，什么？
Or in this case, Eric goes, no, go on, tell me.
或者在这个例子里，埃里克说，不，说吧，告诉我。
What's the latest office gossip?
办公室里最新的八卦是什么？
So obviously he knows it's going to be gossip.
所以很明显他知道这会是八卦。
Right.
没错。
Have you heard?
你听说了吗？
All right.
好吧。
And so the next thing Pam says is, well, you didn't hear this from me.
然后帕姆接下来说的是，嗯，你可别跟别人说是我说的。
Okay.
好的。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
This is typical.
这很典型。
This is a way of saying, okay, don't tell anyone that I told you.
这是一种说法，意思是，好吧，别告诉任何人是我告诉你的。
So you can tell people, but just don't tell them that I said that this happened because
所以你可以告诉别人，但别让他们知道是我说的这件事发生了，因为
Pam doesn't want to get in trouble.
帕姆不想惹麻烦。
Right.
没错。
She doesn't want anyone to know that she was giving out rumors.
她不想让任何人知道她在散布谣言。
So that's why she's starting out with, well, you didn't hear this from me, but the rumor
所以她一开始就说，嗯，你可别跟别人说是我说的，但谣言
is, okay.
是，好吧。
So you can, so this is a way of saying, all right, don't tell anyone that I told you.
所以你可以，这是一种说法，意思是，好吧，别告诉任何人是我告诉你的。
You didn't hear this from me.
你可别跟别人说是我说的。
And also you can go, you can say, but the rumor is, or you can say, but rumor has it.
而且你还可以说，但谣言是，或者你可以说，但据传闻。
Oh, rumor has it that Paula is getting a promotion.
哦，据传闻说宝拉要升职了。
So you can go both ways.
所以两种说法都可以。
And now he exclaimed something that's very strange.
现在他惊呼了一句很奇怪的话。
If you just look at it from these two words, no way.
如果你只看这两个词，“不会吧”。
No way.
不会吧。
What is no way?
“不会吧”是什么意思？
Well, in this context, no way means really?
嗯，在这个语境下，“不会吧”意思是“真的吗？”
Wow.
哇。
Right.
没错。
I'm surprised.
我很惊讶。
So it's a way to express surprise.
所以这是一种表达惊讶的方式。
That's right.
没错。
But be careful because there's another meaning to this phrase.
但要小心，这个短语还有另一个意思。
For example, Marco, could you help me out and get the groceries from the car?
比如，马可，你能帮我从车里拿一下杂货吗？
No way.
没门。
Huh?
嗯？
Okay.
好吧。
That means no.
那意思是“不”。
Okay.
好吧。
No way.
没门。
That means no.
那意思是“不”。
But also if you say it like, no way, you're saying, wow, that's so interesting.
但如果你说“不会吧”，你是在说“哇，真有意思”。
So it can be an expression of surprise or it can be a way of saying no, very firmly,
所以它可以是一种惊讶的表达，也可以是一种非常坚定地说“不”的方式，
no way.
没门。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好吧。
So three great phrases there.
所以这里有三个很棒的短语。
Very interesting dialogue about gossip, very common in the office environment.
关于八卦的对话非常有趣，在办公室环境里很常见。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit.
那我们再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Psst.
嘘。
Hey, Eric, have you heard?
嘿，埃里克，你听说了吗？
No.
没有。
Go on.
说吧。
Tell me.
告诉我。
What's the latest office gossip?
办公室里最新的八卦是什么？
Well, you didn't hear this from me, but the rumor is Paula is getting a promotion.
嗯，你可别跟别人说是我说的，但谣言是宝拉要升职了。
No way.
不会吧。
But she's a terrible worker and you can't trust her.
但她工作很差劲，而且你不能信任她。
She's so two-faced.
她太两面三刀了。
You can't believe anything she says.
她说的任何话你都不能信。
Hey guys.
嘿，伙计们。
What are you two whispering about?
你们俩在嘀咕什么呢？
Oh, hi Paula.
哦，嗨，宝拉。
How are you?
你好吗？
I've got some good news.
我有好消息。
I'm getting a promotion.
我要升职了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Eric and I were just saying that you were the best person for the job.
埃里克和我刚才还在说你是最适合这个职位的人。
Yes.
是的。
You're the best.
你最棒了。
Okay.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So office gossip is generally, well, it's common.
所以办公室八卦一般来说，嗯，很常见。
It happens in every office, but I think that it's good to avoid too much gossip because
每个办公室都会发生，但我认为最好避免太多八卦，因为
sometimes people's feelings can get hurt.
有时候别人的感情会受到伤害。
Yeah.
嗯。
It's actually very interesting because usually the bigger the company is, I think more gossip
其实挺有意思的，通常公司越大，我觉得八卦
starts to spread because there are departments.
就越容易传播，因为部门多。
So you got the marketing department, the finance department.
所以有市场部、财务部。
So you're like, oh, Kathy from finance, she slept with Tom from marketing and stuff like
你就会想，哦，财务部的凯西，她和市场部的汤姆睡了之类的
that.
事情。
Then you have the gossip about the bosses.
然后还有关于老板的八卦。
Right.
对。
Did you see?
你看到了吗？
He totally left for the weekend, but his wife was at home.
他周末完全走了，但他老婆在家。
And also one of the situations where a lot of rumors and office gossip starts to come
还有一种情况，很多谣言和办公室八卦开始
up is office parties or the office Christmas parties where people maybe are drinking or
出现，就是办公室派对或办公室圣诞派对，人们可能喝酒或
something happens and a lot of rumors start to spread.
发生什么事，然后很多谣言就开始传播。
And they're more relaxed than usual.
而且他们比平时更放松。
They do things they wouldn't normally do.
他们会做平时不会做的事。
Absolutely.
绝对。
So maybe we could open this up to you.
所以也许我们可以把话题抛给你。
Is there a common rumor or office gossip that you hear in your office?
你办公室里有没有常见的谣言或办公室八卦？
Or is there that one secretary or guy that's always spreading rumors and gossiping?
或者有没有那么一个秘书或家伙，总是散布谣言和八卦？
And don't use any real names.
别用真名。
You can just tell us general stories.
你只需告诉我们一般的故事。
But that's about it for us here today at EnglishPod.
但今天在EnglishPod我们就聊到这里。
Hope you've enjoyed this.
希望你喜欢这期节目。
Check out our website EnglishPod.com.
访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
Let us know if you have any questions or concerns.
如果有任何问题或疑虑，请告诉我们。
But until next time.
但下次再见。
Bye.
拜拜。
gasp
倒吸一口气